<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Presentations on Nick Galbreath</title><link>https://www.client9.com/tags/presentations/</link><description>Recent content in Presentations on Nick Galbreath</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Nick Galbreath</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.client9.com/tags/presentations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Positive Outcomes from Zero Days</title><link>https://www.client9.com/positive-outcomes-from-zero-days/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/positive-outcomes-from-zero-days/</guid><description>In March 2017 the RAND Corporation released a report “Zero Days, Thousands of Nights: The Life and Times of Zero-Day Vulnerabilities and Their Exploits”. The goal was to assess the public policy of governments stockpiling or releasing so-called 0-day exploits. While that remains an open question, the report and underlying data set of real-world exploits provides valuable insights into software engineering for security and resilience. This talk will provide an overview of the report and what it means for builders and defenders.</description></item><item><title>Resilient Software Engineering</title><link>https://www.client9.com/resilient-software-engineering/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/resilient-software-engineering/</guid><description>As the velocity of application development has increased, so has the velocity (and success) of attackers. Given a massive hiring shortage of security professionals, how can we keep up and even get ahead? We can, if we change the role of security to one that is building systems that are resilient to security shocks. When we do this, we find the topics in security are quite different from what they used to be: How are we managing our software supply chain?</description></item><item><title>Secure Application Development with Golang</title><link>https://www.client9.com/secure-application-development-with-golang/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/secure-application-development-with-golang/</guid><description>First presented at RSA USA 2015, Session ASD-F02 on April 24, 2015 in San Francisco, California.
This might be the worst slide template I have ever used:
Fonts are too small Fonts are microsoft-specific Font color is grey Background is grey Background has pattern It would seem it’s specifically designed for not-reading. But if you can read it, the deck is still accurate in 2018.</description></item><item><title>libinjection: From SQLI to XSS v2</title><link>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-from-sqli-to-xss-v2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-from-sqli-to-xss-v2/</guid><description>“libinjection: From SQLI to XSS” (version 2) was first presented at Code Blue, Tokyo Japan on 2014-02-18, in English and 日本語.</description></item><item><title>libinjection: From SQLI to XSS v1</title><link>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-from-sqli-to-xss-v1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-from-sqli-to-xss-v1/</guid><description>“libinjection: From SQLI to XSS” (version 1) was first presented at OWASP AppSec SoCal, in Santa Monica, California.</description></item><item><title>Making Operations Visible</title><link>https://www.client9.com/making-operations-visible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/making-operations-visible/</guid><description> Video More DevOpsDays Tokyo Coverage Not necessarily related to this presentation.
Video Media posts https://itpro.nikkeibp.co.jp/article/NEWS/20130930/507682/ https://itpro.nikkeibp.co.jp/article/NEWS/20130930/507755/ https://itpro.nikkeibp.co.jp/article/NEWS/20131001/507959/ https://www.publickey1.jp/blog/13/devopsdevops_day_tokyo_2013.html https://www.publickey1.jp/blog/13/devopsdevops_day_tokyo_2013_1.html https://www.publickey1.jp/blog/13/githubdevopsboxenhubotdevops_day_tokyo_2013.html https://www.publickey1.jp/blog/13/githubboxenhubotdevops_day_tokyo_2013.html https://www.publickey1.jp/blog/13/devopsdevops_day_tokyo_2013_2.html Attendee posts https://mass.hatenablog.com/entry/2013/09/28/205309 https://d.hatena.ne.jp/n-sega/20130928/1380373634 https://kazuph.hateblo.jp/entry/2013/09/28/152302 https://jedipunkz.github.io/blog/2013/09/29/devops-day-tokyo-2013-report/ https://toshi-miura.hatenablog.com/entry/2013/09/29/222609 https://codezine.jp/article/detail/7438</description></item><item><title>Faster Secure Software Development with Continuous Deployment</title><link>https://www.client9.com/faster-secure-software-development-with-continuous-deployment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/faster-secure-software-development-with-continuous-deployment/</guid><description>First presented at PHDays on May 24, 2013 in Moscow, Russia.
Why don&amp;#39;t developers care about security issues? Why isn&amp;#39;t security training effective? Why do basic application security problems continue to exist? One reason is that long release cycles disenfranchise developers from caring or even knowing about security or operational issues. Continuous Deployment helps address this by small, but frequent, changes to the production environment. At first, this would seem less stable and less secure, however continuous deployment is a lot more than &amp;#34;pushing code&amp;#34;.</description></item><item><title>Fixing Security by Fixing Development using Continuous Deployment</title><link>https://www.client9.com/fixing-security-by-fixing-development-using-continuous-deployment/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/fixing-security-by-fixing-development-using-continuous-deployment/</guid><description>First presented at Security Development Conference on May 14, 2013 in San Francisco, USA.
Do you have an effective release cycle? Is your process long and archaic? Long release cycle are typically based on assumptions we haven&amp;#39;t seen since the 1980s and require very mature organizations to implement successfully. They can also disenfranchise developers from caring or even knowing about security or operational issues. Attend this session to learn more about an alternative approach to managing deployments through Continuous Deployment, otherwise known as Continuous Delivery.</description></item><item><title>Care and Feeding of Large Scale Graphite Installations</title><link>https://www.client9.com/care-and-feeding-of-large-scale-graphite-installations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/care-and-feeding-of-large-scale-graphite-installations/</guid><description>First presented at DevOpsDays on May 1, 2013 in Austin, Texas.</description></item><item><title>SQL-RISC New Directions in SQLi Prevention</title><link>https://www.client9.com/sql-risc-new-directions-in-sqli-prevention/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/sql-risc-new-directions-in-sqli-prevention/</guid><description>First presented at RSA USA 2013 on February 27, 2013 in San Francisco, California.</description></item><item><title>Rebooting (secure) (web) software development with Continuous Deployment</title><link>https://www.client9.com/rebooting-secure-web-software-development-with-continuous-deployment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/rebooting-secure-web-software-development-with-continuous-deployment/</guid><description>First presented at OWASP AppSec USA on October 25, 2012 in Austin, Texas.
Original Abstract:
If we are ever going to get ahead of the whack-a-mole security vulnerability game, we, as security professionals need to start getting involved more in the development of software. Let&amp;#39;s review the origins of the traditional software development, and what assumptions are made. Then we&amp;#39;ll review if those assumptions still hold for modern web applications, and what problems they cause, especially for security.</description></item><item><title>libinjection and SQLi Obfuscation</title><link>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-and-sqli-obfuscation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-and-sqli-obfuscation/</guid><description>First presented at OWASP NYC on September 20, 2012 at DTCC&amp;#39;s headquarters on 55 Water Street, New York City.</description></item><item><title>libinjection: New Techniques in Detecting SQLi Attacks</title><link>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-new-techniques-in-detecting-sqli-attacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-new-techniques-in-detecting-sqli-attacks/</guid><description>First presented at iSEC Partners Open Forum on September 6, 2012 at Gilt Group, New York City.</description></item><item><title>Continuous Deployment, The New Number One Security Feature</title><link>https://www.client9.com/continuous-deployment-the-new-number-one-security-feature/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/continuous-deployment-the-new-number-one-security-feature/</guid><description>First presented at Security BSides Los Angeles on August 16, 2012 in Hermosa Beach, California.</description></item><item><title>New Techniques in SQLi Obfuscation</title><link>https://www.client9.com/new-techniques-in-sqli-obfuscation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/new-techniques-in-sqli-obfuscation/</guid><description>First presented Friday July 27, 2012 at DEFCON 20, Las Vegas, NV, at the RIO on 4:20pm.
Original abstract:
SQLi remains a popular sport in the security arms-race. However, after analysis of hundreds of thousands of real world SQLi attacks, output from SQLi scanners, published reports, analysis of WAF source code, and database vendor documentation, both SQLi attackers and defenders have missed a few opportunities. This talk will iterate through the dark corners of SQL for use in new obfuscated attacks, and show why they are problematic for regular-expression based WAFs.</description></item><item><title>libinjection: a C library for SQLi detection</title><link>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-a-c-library-for-sqli-detection/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/libinjection-a-c-library-for-sqli-detection/</guid><description>First presented Wednesday July 25, 2012 at Black Hat USA, Las Vegas, NV. Augustus I/II at 2:45pm.
From the original abstract:
SQLi and other injection attacks remain the top OWASP and CERT vulnerability. Current detection attempts frequently involve a myriad of regular expressions which are not only brittle and error prone but also proven by Hanson and Patterson at Black Hat 2005 to never be a complete solution. libinjection is a new open source C library that detects SQLi using lexical analysis.</description></item><item><title>Time Tested PHP: Advanced Testing Techniques with libtimemachine</title><link>https://www.client9.com/time-tested-php-advanced-testing-techniques-with-libtimemachine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/time-tested-php-advanced-testing-techniques-with-libtimemachine/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Static Analysis for PHP</title><link>https://www.client9.com/static-analysis-for-php/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/static-analysis-for-php/</guid><description>Also checkout the matching Code as Craft article on static analysis for PHP.</description></item><item><title>Rate-Limiting at Scale</title><link>https://www.client9.com/rate-limiting-at-scale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/rate-limiting-at-scale/</guid><description>Rate Limiting in Action Nick Galbreath, Director of Engineering, Etsy. Rate limiting is a useful technique to limit malicious and undesirable behavior on web services. This talk will present a simple rate limit implementation using memcached that allows one to easily add rate limiting anywhere in their application. We’ll then cover some (surprising) real-world uses of rate limits, how to distinguish between enthusiasm and maliciousness, and finally some of the common countermeasures that are used.</description></item><item><title>What You Can Learn From Small Companies about AppSec</title><link>https://www.client9.com/what-you-can-learn-from-small-companies-about-appsec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/what-you-can-learn-from-small-companies-about-appsec/</guid><description>This was presented at SANS AppSec Summit, Las Vegas on April 30 2012. None of the presenters are really from “small companies,” but still useful seeing how different companies solve security problems.
4:05-5:00 p.m.What You Can Learn From Small Companies About AppSecModerator: SANS InstitutePanelists:Jim Bird, CTO, BIDS Trading TechnologiesNick Galbreath, Director of Engineering, EtsyCameron Morris, Software Security Specialist , PartNetApplication security is a big challenge for small organizations, too. The security problems are just as numerous, but the resources are fewer.</description></item><item><title>DevOpsSec Applying DevOps Principles to Security</title><link>https://www.client9.com/devopssec-applying-devops-principles-to-security/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/devopssec-applying-devops-principles-to-security/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fraud Engineering: Implementing a Cross-Functional Risk Strategy</title><link>https://www.client9.com/fraud-engineering-implementing-a-cross-functional-risk-strategy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.client9.com/fraud-engineering-implementing-a-cross-functional-risk-strategy/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>